<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pitching | Jaihonikhil</title>
    <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/pitching/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/pitching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Pitching</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/media/icon_hu94c20572586274a900963e2d3893d162_15641_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Pitching</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/pitching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>STUDENTBUILD4COVID19 International Hackathon (USA) Teamc- RapiDoc&#43;</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/studentbuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/studentbuild/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDBHAV 2020 (The Innovation Festival, IIT Kanpur)</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/udbhav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/udbhav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This competition was organized by the Startup Incubation Center, IIT Kanpur for selecting top Start-Up ideas for funding and supporting them at the Seed stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had pitched the Customer, Product, Company and Competition component for the idea Preliminary Detection of Pulmonary Detection which was our Inter IIT Techmeet Project.Our Business model estimated a Market Size of 6.5 Lakh Health Centers and an INR 24 Million per Annum Revenue from sales of the App and the Hardware. Allover the idea was very impressive and we were awarded with the 3rd Prize and a cash prize as well. Our idea was also called out for funding by the SIIC Center, IIT Kanpur!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Detection of Pulmonary Diseases</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/proejct3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/proejct3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early detection of Pulmonary diseases like Aastma, Tuberculosis, COPD ,Bronchiolitis etc through non-invasive method. This project was done keeping in mind a competition &amp;ldquo;Tech For Change&amp;rdquo; in Inter IIT Techmeet 2019 in IIT Rorkee.The slides presented are attached as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the fatalities caused by pulmonary disorders such as COPD, asthma, bronchiolitis etc. could be prevented by timely diagnosis of the patients. Combined with the extreme lack of medical practitioners and infrastructure in rural areas, the lack of screening programs, which would provide such timely diagnosis, has made pulmonary diseases the second most deadliest kind in India. To make such screening programs more practical and feasible, we propose an automated procedure for the screening of the rural populations, using an easy-to-use device that can be operated even by a community worker. As a proof of concept, we have developed a novel device to record auscultation sounds and the breathing rate of the patient. On this data, a machine learning model with Keras framework and Tensorflow backend is implemented to detect abnormalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 3 dense layer and a dropout layer convolutional neural network is used to identify Wheezes and Crackles in an audio file which is fed as Mel-Spectrograms as inputs. Data augmentation was employed in the form of audio stretching as well as Vocal Tract Length Perturbation, especially for the scarcer &amp;lsquo;wheeze&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;wheeze and crackles&amp;rsquo; classes. Overall validation accuracy currently stands at roughly 80 percent. On the user interface side, the mobile application displays an immediate report of the patient displaying the diseases which are suggested by the symptoms observed. Such automation using an inexpensive device removes the dependency on doctors and expensive equipment, which makes the screening programs impractical for large scale implementation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were awarded silver medal in this competition !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non Invasive Glucometer</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/pitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution Concept&lt;/strong&gt;
NIR Analysis and Pulse Oximetry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitched the Business model for BETiC- Non Invasive Glucometer depicting market size, penetration rate, profit and estimated sales revenue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Novelty&lt;/strong&gt;
NIR Analysis along with Pulse Oximetry with multi-variable regression solve the purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;
One-step, easy to follow procedure
Useful for patients with high, low as well as normal sugar values
No risk of spread of viral agents
Cost-effective solution in the long run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;
A one-time-buy product that gives accurate results throughout its lifetime
Multiple people can use the same device, hence it is cost-effective
Only needs change of batteries with time&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
