<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing is Relieving | Jaihonikhil</title>
    <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/writing-is-relieving/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/writing-is-relieving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Writing is Relieving</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/media/icon_hu94c20572586274a900963e2d3893d162_15641_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Writing is Relieving</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/tag/writing-is-relieving/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What took me so lo_ong to start Blogging?</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Salut!╰(* °▽° *)╯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer: This is a personal blog written for the sole purpose of the satisfaction of talking to someone in a way that the writer finds satisfying. In addition to it do not try to interpret the emogis in the blog 🍕&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always wanted to be an original and the thought of writing or documenting things has always excited me. Besides Blogging, I have always wanted to cover songs and post them for my own satisfaction. But somehow couldn&amp;rsquo;t because of my own insecurities, the people around me, and the thought that publicizing oneself was a cheap stunt. (I&amp;rsquo;m wrong here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, somehow I realized in the past year that my life is short, I have sooo many dreams to accomplish, soo many amazing people to meet and sooo much help to give. I have always loved meeting new people, getting to know them, and mainly how differently everyone thinks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to sit here and wait for things to happen, I&amp;rsquo;m going to make them happen, and if people think I&amp;rsquo;m an idiot I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So considering everything, if I have 50–60ish more years to live and so many dreams to achieve, I need to be alive and not just living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how my blogs are gonna turn out or even if they would even matter to anyone. But does it even matter when you are just an amateur open to ideas, risks, and suggestions(HINT HINT)❗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OHKAY Jaya Speak the Truth!!🌊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I like talking and why not? and I have these so many wonderful ideas, thoughts, and experiences in my head and while I am exploring so many things at this stage, I can&amp;rsquo;t contain everything in my head without venting it out anywhere. So this blog is possibly an effort to pour my heart out, speak my mind and hear my thoughts. Also in a way, helping me to think clearly and taking control of my thoughts or rather they taking control over me❓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I am mainly writing to deal with anxiety, guilt, and self-hatred. I have been feeling miserable, wrongly done, hurt, and lost for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire for answers and conquest over anxiety and mental issues, paired with an inability to never being able to overcome or find the source, control, and understanding of the problem has eventually led me to start finding things that are beautiful about me and appreciating the world around. I am trying to reason and understand how to overcome because I can&amp;rsquo;t give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t the fact that you are hurt that counts,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But only How did you take it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well in addition to it who knows I might meet amazing people with similar thoughts and make new friends!💁‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I am just beginning so if you are reading this blog, you will notice the improvement in the content and mentality gradually so please be patient with me. I am all raw and honest here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The more man meditates upon good thoughts,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the better will be his world and the world at large !&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONFUCIOUS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! I will end this blog on a positive note with lines that touch my heart and might help a wanderer ……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t the fact that you are dead that counts,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But only How did you die?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers, and I&amp;rsquo;m extremely grateful to you for being a reader 😸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 1. The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site
2. The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&#39;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a **no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)** and having **flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS**
3. You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;figure-img-wrap&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


## Get Started

- 👉 [**Create a new site**](https://wowchemy.com/templates/)
- 📚 [**Personalize your site**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/)
- 💬 [Chat with the **Wowchemy community**](https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb) or [**Hugo community**](https://discourse.gohugo.io)
- 🐦 Twitter: [@wowchemy](https://twitter.com/wowchemy) [@GeorgeCushen](https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen) [#MadeWithWowchemy](https://twitter.com/search?q=(%23MadeWithWowchemy%20OR%20%23MadeWithAcademic)&amp;src=typed_query)
- 💡 [Request a **feature** or report a **bug** for _Wowchemy_](https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues)
- ⬆️ **Updating Wowchemy?** View the [Update Guide](https://wowchemy.com/docs/guide/update/) and [Release Notes](https://wowchemy.com/updates/)

## Crowd-funded open-source software



### [❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&#39;s future ❤️](https://wowchemy.com/plans/)

As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can **unlock [these](https://wowchemy.com/plans/) awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨**

## Ecosystem

* **[Hugo Academic CLI](https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli):** Automatically import publications from BibTeX

## Inspiration

[Check out the latest **demo**](https://academic-demo.netlify.com/) of what you&#39;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or [view the **showcase**](https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/) of personal, project, and business sites.

## Features

- **Page builder** - Create *anything* with [**widgets**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/) and [**elements**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/)
- **Edit any type of content** - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!
- **Create content** in [**Markdown**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/), [**Jupyter**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/), or [**RStudio**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/)
- **Plugin System** - Fully customizable [**color** and **font themes**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/)
- **Display Code and Math** - Code highlighting and [LaTeX math](https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics) supported
- **Integrations** - [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com), [Disqus commenting](https://disqus.com), Maps, Contact Forms, and more!
- **Beautiful Site** - Simple and refreshing one page design
- **Industry-Leading SEO** - Help get your website found on search engines and social media
- **Media Galleries** - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery
- **Mobile Friendly** - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site
- **Multi-language** - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português
- **Multi-user** - Each author gets their own profile page
- **Privacy Pack** - Assists with GDPR
- **Stand Out** - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects
- **One-Click Deployment** - No servers. No databases. Only files.

## Themes

Wowchemy and its templates come with **automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode** built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the [Demo](https://academic-demo.netlify.com/) to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in `params.toml`.

[Choose a stunning **theme** and **font**](https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization) for your site. Themes are fully customizable.

## License

Copyright 2016-present [George Cushen](https://georgecushen.com).

Released under the [MIT](https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md) license.  --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
