<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jaihonikhil</title>
    <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/media/icon_hu94c20572586274a900963e2d3893d162_15641_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement Verification and Evidence Finding using Tables</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tables are ubiquitous in documents and presentations for conveying important information in a concise manner. This is true in many domains, stretching from scientific to government documents.  In fact,  surrounding text in these articles are often statements summarizing or highlighting some information derived from the primary source data in tables. Describing all the information provided in a table in a readable manner would be lengthy and considerably more difficult to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, there has been an interest in factual verification and prediction over structured data like tables and graphs. To circumvent any false news incident, it is necessary to not only model and predict over structured data efficiently but also to explain those predictions. In this paper, as part of the SemEval-2021 Task 9,  we tackle the problem of fact verification and evidence finding over tabular data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two subtasks. Given a table and a statement/fact, subtask A determines whether the statement is inferred from the tabular data, and subtask B determines which cells in the table provide evidence for the former subtask. We make a comparison of the baselines and state-of-the-art approaches over the given SemTabFact dataset. We also propose a novel approach CellBERT to solve evidence finding as a form of the Natural Language Inference task. We obtain a &lt;strong&gt;3-way F1 score of 0.69 on subtask A&lt;/strong&gt; and an &lt;strong&gt;F1 score of 0.65 on subtask B&lt;/strong&gt;. We were &lt;strong&gt;5th in Subtask A&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;1st in Subtask B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigate the Mars Rover (The Mars Colonization Program)</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/example2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/example2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a project/ competition offered by Microsoft India to the selected students as a part of the Engage Mentorship Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project required to implement and innovate the Pathfinding Library. As a result, We implemented a new heuristics added to our pathfinding visualizer by the name of Optimized Manhatten. Having tested the heuristic on benchmark, we have managed time reduction by approx 50% in case of Astar algorithm and approx 15% reduction in time in Best First Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The length of path and number of operations remain unaltered, hence we have not applied greedy algorithm to reduce time and compromise on the optimal path. We have also added an option of speed in the naivigation bar, the speed with which the rover reaches the space station can be managed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gateway Heuristic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maze and patterns present in the repository were added to test a new heuristic called the Gateway heuristic. The gateway heuristic pre-calculates the distances between entrances/exits of the areas. It also proceeds in two phases. Preprocessing Phase: The map is decomposed into areas in an identical way as for the dead-end heuristic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We define the boundaries between areas as gateways (or gates). A gateway can be of an arbitrary size, but an artifact of our decomposition algorithm is that its orientation is always either horizontal or vertical. Next we use multiple A* searches to pre-calculate the (static) distance between gates. For each gateway we calculate the path distance to all the other gateways (cost of infinity if no path exists). Alternatively, one could calculate only the distances between gateways within each room and then use a small search to accumulate the total cost during run-time. However, our approach results in more accurate heuristic estimates and faster run-time access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STUDENTBUILD4COVID19 International Hackathon (USA) Teamc- RapiDoc&#43;</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/studentbuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/studentbuild/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techno Advanced Disinfection Tunnel</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project44/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TADT is a robust autonomous disinfection tunnel to disinfect external surfaces of COVID-19 virus such as clothes and open body sections in public places such as airports, office complexes, schools, and malls. To make the tunnel effective and highly efficient, it has been provided with two chambers with three disinfection processes. Due to the multiple processes, the possibility of neutralizing the virus is quite high and higher than other solutions available at this point for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chamber 1 sprays the solution of a disinfectant on the person. This solution can be either a dilute solution of approved chemical or any Ayurvedic/herbal disinfectant. Once the person enters chamber 2, he/she is exposed to hot air at 70 °C along with far-ultraviolet C rays (207–222 nm). Both chambers function autonomously by detecting a person in a chamber using ultrasonic sensors. The proposed tunnel is developed under industry–academia collaboration jointly by Technopark@iitk and ALIMCO under the ambit of the Ministry of Human Resources Development and the Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment, respectively. The tunnel is referred to as the ‘Techno Advanced Disinfection Tunnel’ (TADT).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised abnormality detection by using intelligent and heterogeneous autonomous systems( IEEE Signal Processing Cup )</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the competition required to do Unsupervised abnormality detection by using intelligent and heterogeneous autonomous systems where the goal was to detect abnormalities in the behaviour of the ground and aerial systems based on embedded sensor data in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomous systems experience failure when the sensors record abnormal data which leads to the crashing of the decision making module if it is not capable of detecting abnormalities. The design of abnormality detection models becomes
an important step in preventing the autonomous systems from
malfunctioning. The organisers of SP cup have provided the dataset
consisting of data from various sensors mounted on a drone.
After identifying the key challenges like limited training data,
non-uniformity in sampling of data from different sensors, low
FPS of camera, absence of ground truth annotations, we have used isolation
forest method, CNN based timeforecasting method and ARMA
model based timeforecasting method to detect the abnormality.
We compare these methods using the performance metric of
Excess Mass Curves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were 6th internationally in this competition !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UDBHAV 2020 (The Innovation Festival, IIT Kanpur)</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/udbhav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/udbhav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This competition was organized by the Startup Incubation Center, IIT Kanpur for selecting top Start-Up ideas for funding and supporting them at the Seed stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had pitched the Customer, Product, Company and Competition component for the idea Preliminary Detection of Pulmonary Detection which was our Inter IIT Techmeet Project.Our Business model estimated a Market Size of 6.5 Lakh Health Centers and an INR 24 Million per Annum Revenue from sales of the App and the Hardware. Allover the idea was very impressive and we were awarded with the 3rd Prize and a cash prize as well. Our idea was also called out for funding by the SIIC Center, IIT Kanpur!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Detection of Pulmonary Diseases</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/proejct3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/proejct3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early detection of Pulmonary diseases like Aastma, Tuberculosis, COPD ,Bronchiolitis etc through non-invasive method. This project was done keeping in mind a competition &amp;ldquo;Tech For Change&amp;rdquo; in Inter IIT Techmeet 2019 in IIT Rorkee.The slides presented are attached as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the fatalities caused by pulmonary disorders such as COPD, asthma, bronchiolitis etc. could be prevented by timely diagnosis of the patients. Combined with the extreme lack of medical practitioners and infrastructure in rural areas, the lack of screening programs, which would provide such timely diagnosis, has made pulmonary diseases the second most deadliest kind in India. To make such screening programs more practical and feasible, we propose an automated procedure for the screening of the rural populations, using an easy-to-use device that can be operated even by a community worker. As a proof of concept, we have developed a novel device to record auscultation sounds and the breathing rate of the patient. On this data, a machine learning model with Keras framework and Tensorflow backend is implemented to detect abnormalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 3 dense layer and a dropout layer convolutional neural network is used to identify Wheezes and Crackles in an audio file which is fed as Mel-Spectrograms as inputs. Data augmentation was employed in the form of audio stretching as well as Vocal Tract Length Perturbation, especially for the scarcer &amp;lsquo;wheeze&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;wheeze and crackles&amp;rsquo; classes. Overall validation accuracy currently stands at roughly 80 percent. On the user interface side, the mobile application displays an immediate report of the patient displaying the diseases which are suggested by the symptoms observed. Such automation using an inexpensive device removes the dependency on doctors and expensive equipment, which makes the screening programs impractical for large scale implementation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were awarded silver medal in this competition !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non Invasive Glucometer</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/pitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/pitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution Concept&lt;/strong&gt;
NIR Analysis and Pulse Oximetry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitched the Business model for BETiC- Non Invasive Glucometer depicting market size, penetration rate, profit and estimated sales revenue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Novelty&lt;/strong&gt;
NIR Analysis along with Pulse Oximetry with multi-variable regression solve the purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;
One-step, easy to follow procedure
Useful for patients with high, low as well as normal sugar values
No risk of spread of viral agents
Cost-effective solution in the long run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;
A one-time-buy product that gives accurate results throughout its lifetime
Multiple people can use the same device, hence it is cost-effective
Only needs change of batteries with time&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERNATIONAL ROBOTICS CHALLENGE</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/robotics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed an Autonomous Pathplanning bot and a Manual bot with scissor mechanism and a gripper, controlled through PS2 for removing the obstacles in the maze&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helped in the electrical part of the Robots as well through the connections with the motors, Ultrasonic sensors, Arduino, and servos&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WITRACK Wireless tracking of humans through wal</title>
      <link>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaihonikhil.github.io/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;​WiTrack is a device that tracks the 3-D motion of the user from the radio signals reflected off their body. It works even if the person is occluded from the WiTrack device or in a different room.  WiTrack does not require the user to wear any kind of wearable device. It transmits wireless signals whose power is significantly lower than Wi-Fi or cellular transmissions. It can be incorporated into consumer electronics and has a wide set of applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device transmits a radio signal and uses its reflections to estimate the time it takes the signal to travel from the transmitting antenna to the reflecting object and back to each of the receiving antennas. WiTrack then uses its knowledge of the position of the antennas to create a geometric reference model, which maps the round trip delays observed by the receive antennas to a 3D position of the reflecting body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this Project, our team and the project was awareded the Best Research and Development Award by the Science and Technology Council, IIT Kanpur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Project was inspired by the Witrack Project of MIT under Professor Dina Katabi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
